<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi there! on Trollcode.no - A personal blog</title>
    <link>//www.trollcode.no/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi there! on Trollcode.no - A personal blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//www.trollcode.no/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo and VS Code Dev Containers</title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-09-19-hugo-dev-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-09-19-hugo-dev-container/</guid>
      <description>Last month I revamped my old blog. I figured I wanted to write more blog articles and needed a easy platform to do so. I had previously been using Jekyll and had been quite happy. But after a look at Hugo I wanted to give that a try. Really just for the &amp;ldquo;kicks of it&amp;rdquo;.
Both are static website generators. But Hugo offers some more bells and whistles that I wanted to make use of like Shortcodes and easy templating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python introduction workshop with cheat sheet</title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-09-06-python-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-09-06-python-workshop/</guid>
      <description>This post has an associated public github repository. Go check it out if you like!Some time ago I was asked by my employer if I could hold a introductory workshop in Python for two of our office locations. My Python knowledge is not all that, but I have recently (over the last year or so) started to like programming using the language. So I set out to create a workshop that I think could be productive very fast as long as you know the basics of programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting viewer statistics from Twitch API using Azure Functions</title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-08-29-twitch-data-using-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-08-29-twitch-data-using-functions/</guid>
      <description>This post has an associated public github repository. Check out the entire solution here on Github.I have live-coded a few times on Twitch now. And I think it is a great platform for both learning and trying to give back to the community by streaming and putting information out there for others to learn from. On Twitch all streams have to belong to one &amp;ldquo;category&amp;rdquo;. These categories are called games on Twitch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/talk/06-19-ndc-azure-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 17:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/talk/06-19-ndc-azure-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Azure is a great platform to use when creating your next minimal viable product (MVP).
But some services are more expensive than others. And in this talk I will show that instead of going straight to the more expensive options for your MVP, there are many cheap options available on the Azure platform. Some services even have a free-tier.
Using Azure Storage Accounts for your data storage needs, Azure Functions or Azure Container Instances for your API and computing needs can make for a very cheap and low maintenance MVP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/talk/04-19-azure-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/talk/04-19-azure-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft Azure has in short time become one of the three largest cloud providers. In this talk we will have a look at what Microsoft Azure is and what it can it can offer to you as a developer. A description of some of the most used services that are offered, as well as a introduction to those services will be given. Some services works better in some situations than others, and my personal experience from misc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going serverless with Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-04-03-going-serverless-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2019-04-03-going-serverless-azure/</guid>
      <description>This article have been posted on my employers official blog at an earlier time. They are the same. My post on my employers website can be found here: Webstep - Going serverless with Microsoft Azure The term “serverless” is something that we hear more and more about. It is mentioned often as the next big thing in cloud computing. There might be a small confusion on to what serverless really is, and it does not help that the cloud providers often “serverless-wash” their existing services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/talk/04-18-azure-datalake-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/talk/04-18-azure-datalake-intro/</guid>
      <description>In Norwegian:
Presentasjon gitt til Webstep Sørlandet som tar for seg Azure Datalake en introduksjon til dette. Den går inn på temaer som Azure Datalake Storage, Azure Datalake Analytics, U-SQL, Azure Data Factory og tips &amp;amp; triks som jeg har lært den tiden jeg har drevet på med dette emnet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/talk/03-18-azure-introduction-for-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/talk/03-18-azure-introduction-for-java/</guid>
      <description>In Norwegian:
Microsoft har også en skyløsning, og den har på kort tid blitt en av de største, om ikke størst. Microsoft Azure tilbyr mye av de samme mulighetene som Amazon AWS, og støtter både Java, C# og flere andre programmeringsspråk. Karl Syvert Løland fra NorgesEnergi vil fortelle mer om Azure og de ulike modellene Microsoft tilbyr for utvikling, deriblant Service Fabric og Functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/talk/06-17-quick-osdev-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/talk/06-17-quick-osdev-intro/</guid>
      <description>Karl Syvert Løland from NorgesEnergi will tells us the why&amp;rsquo;s and how&amp;rsquo;s about developing his very own operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/talk/10-17-ndc-quick-osdev-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2017 19:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/talk/10-17-ndc-quick-osdev-intro/</guid>
      <description>This lightning talk will give an introduction to operating system development and how to get started. It is easier than one might think and can be a very fun and rewarding experience.
There exists many myths that OS dev is hard. My goal is to show that OS dev is easy to learn but difficult to master. The talk will be low on technical terms and take a more from the top view on how to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting floppy disk drives using CMOS</title>
      <link>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2015-08-01-detecting-floppy-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//www.trollcode.no/blog/2015-08-01-detecting-floppy-disk/</guid>
      <description>As a hobby project I am working on a small OS project for i386 (and ARM). Recently I was writing a driver for floppy disk drives and I stumbled on to a issue that I needed to find a solution for.
The issue was how to detect if any or how many floppy disk drives are present on a given system. I quick google informed me that the CMOS was normally used for this and the page provided some getting started information on how to detect floppy disk drives.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>